This is Minecraft, the game that screwed its community so hard that we're about to sue them in a class action lawsuit.
这就是《我的世界》，一款把玩家社区坑得体无完肤，以至于我们准备对他们提起集体诉讼的游戏。
You see, in December of 2024, I uploaded this video in which I exposed Mojang
你看，在 2024 年 12 月，我上传了这段视频，在视频中我揭露了 Mojang
the creators of Minecraft, for breaking consumer protection law and exposing children to gambling.
也就是《我的世界》的开发商，违反了消费者保护法，并让儿童接触赌博。
And while I tried to seek justice for myself
虽然我曾试图为自己伸张正义
I wasn't able to do so because my government is kind of incompetent
但我却无能为力，因为我的政府有点无能
making access to justice basically impossible if you're not rich as fuck.
如果你不是他妈的有钱人，那么伸张正义基本上是不可能的。
So I tried adding a GoFundMe campaign at the end to finance a class action lawsuit
所以，我尝试在最后添加了一个 GoFundMe 众筹活动，希望能为一场集体诉讼筹集资金
because this wasn't something that affected just me.
因为这件事影响的并非只有我一个人。
And obviously, there's no way that would actually work
很显然，这种方法根本行不通。
right?
对吧？
YouTuber Kiabru- Is suing Mojang.
油管主 Kiabru 正在起诉 Mojang。
Illegally changing- They publicly funded- It's already nearly on a million Gs.
非法更改——他们公开筹款——金额已经快到一百万了。
19 on trending right now.
目前在热门榜单上排名第 19 位。
It's exceeded it.
已经超额完成了。
Completed its funding.
已完成募资。
Already passed- $120,000.
已经超过了——12 万美元。
That's a lot.
这可真不少。
No way the class- Dude, look at this.
这门课不可能——老兄，你看看这个。
That's gotta be one of the fastest-growing crowdfunding campaigns.
这绝对是增长最快的众筹项目之一。
We raised $150,000 within days.
我们在几天内就筹集了 15 万美元。
Oh, it's fucking happening.
哦，这他妈的真的要成了。
Where we now have access to legal representation and can proceed with the class action lawsuit.
我们现在已经获得了法律代表，可以继续进行集体诉讼。
Yes.
是的。
My name is Bjorn Persson.
我叫比约恩·佩尔松。
I'm a member of the Swedish Borrower Association.
我是瑞典借款人协会的成员。
I run a law firm together with my colleague
我和我的同事一起经营着一家律师事务所
Conny Larsson.
他叫康尼·拉尔森。
And we're working with this lawsuit since it's part of our practice and are looking to
我们正在处理这起诉讼，因为这是我们业务的一部分，并且我们希望
um, run this, uh, lawsuit as a class action against Mojang because we think it's an important issue that needs to be addressed.
将这起诉讼作为针对 Mojang 的集体诉讼来处理，因为我们认为这是一个需要解决的重要问题。
To give you a little recap, Minecraft is one of those games that anyone can modify to add things that it didn't originally have.
简单回顾一下，Minecraft 是一款任何人都可以修改的游戏，可以添加一些它原本没有的东西。
And what I wanted to do was add guns to the game to recreate an old game that I used to play as a child that had unfortunately been shut down.
我想做的就是在游戏中加入枪支，以此来重现我小时候玩过的一款游戏，但那款游戏很不幸已经停服了。
But right as it was about to release
但就在它即将发布的时候
Mojang said that, "A recent directive from Mojang leadership determined that guns and weapons were considered non-compliant features.
Mojang 表示：“根据 Mojang 领导层最近的一项指令，枪支和武器被视为不合规的功能。”
" Meaning that they had to be completely removed
意味着它们必须被彻底移除
implying the shutdown of dozens of projects, including mine.
这也就意味着数十个项目将被关停，其中也包括我的项目。
But when actually looking into it, even though they said that guns and weapons were specifically prohibited by the game's legal agreement
但当我真正深入研究时，发现尽管他们声称游戏的法律协议明确禁止枪支和武器
when actually looking for these specific prohibitions, you'd come to find that they didn't actually exist.
当你真正去寻找这些具体的禁令时，你会发现它们其实并不存在。
So Mojang was making shit up and pretending it was part of the Terms of Service
所以 Mojang 其实是在胡编乱造，并假装这些是服务条款的一部分。
a type of contract, which as you've guessed
一种合同，正如你所猜测的
is kind of illegal.
有点不合法。
A contract is an agreement between two parties and both parties need to agree what the meaning of the contract is.
合同是双方之间的协议，双方都需要就合同的含义达成一致。
You can't be forced into new rules that apply to your contract unless you've been notified
除非你收到通知，否则你不能被强迫接受适用于你合同的新规则。
as well as having a choice whether to actually accept those terms or just be able to keep using what you already have.
并且可以选择是接受这些条款，还是继续使用你已有的东西。
And since this is a hidden clause where guns are just one of the many examples that exist
而且由于这是一个隐藏条款，枪支只是众多例子中的一个
Mojang can do whatever they want, like applying a different version of the same clause so you never know which one you're gonna get
Mojang 可以为所欲为，比如应用同一条款的不同版本，所以你永远不知道自己会遇到哪一个。
changing their minds at any time, like they did with the guns three times
随时改变主意，就像他们在枪支问题上三次变卦一样
and even go against their own rules, like allowing gambling even though they publicly pretend like it's forbidden.
甚至违背他们自己定下的规则，比如他们公开假装禁止赌博，却又允许赌博的存在。
But obviously, shit gets worse.
但很显然，事情变得更糟了。
Because when a company changes its terms of service
因为当公司更改服务条款时
it's required to notify its users about the changes and get their agreement for it.
它需要通知用户这些变更，并征得他们的同意。
And out of the 47 times they changed their legal agreements
在他们 47 次更改法律协议的过程中
they never told anyone about it.
他们从未告诉任何人这件事。
We know this because I went through thousands of archived pages for every single legal agreement that the game has ever had to see if a single word had changed.
我们之所以知道这一点，是因为我查阅了这款游戏有史以来所有法律协议的上千页存档，想看看是否有一个字被改动过。
And Mojang not notifying anyone of changes makes perfect sense
而 Mojang 不通知任何人这些变更，是完全说得通的。
since in their own words, "It is up to you to check back to see if these guidelines have changed
因为用他们自己的话来说，“您有责任回来查看这些指南是否已更改”
" so that it's not their responsibility to tell you.
这样一来，他们就没有责任通知您了。
There's a lot of things that you really can't do with the contract and have it enforceable against the consumers.
有很多事情，你是无法通过合同来强制消费者履行的。
You have this legislation under European consumer law that
根据欧洲消费者法，有这样一项法规
uh, mandates that the company that changes
它强制要求变更条款的公司
uh, the terms need to inform the consumers about this.
需要将变更情况告知消费者。
And they can't enforce the, the new changes without giving
而且，如果不给消费者一个选择，他们就无法强制执行这些新的变更。
uh, the consumers a choice.
呃，消费者有权选择。
And if not telling anyone wasn't already bad enough- They removed the notice when the software terms were updated.
如果说不告知任何人还不够糟糕的话——他们在更新软件条款时，甚至移除了相关通知。
This is obviously making it harder for the consumers to exercise their rights.
这显然让消费者更难行使其权利。
Because not only is it our responsibility to check when changes happen
因为我们不仅有责任在发生变更时进行核查，
but they also make it borderline impossible to tell when they actually did.
而且他们还让我们几乎无法判断变更究竟是何时发生的。
Which is quite ironic coming from the company that says
这对于那家宣称...的公司来说，相当讽刺。
"We are trying to be open, honest
“我们正努力做到开放、诚实”
and most importantly, trusting.
“最重要的是，值得信赖。”
" But of course, it only gets worse.
当然，事情只会变得更糟。
Remember how the original email from Mojang said that guns were specifically prohibited by these three legal agreements where one of them didn't even exist?
还记得 Mojang 最初的邮件里是怎么说的吗？他们说，根据三份法律协议，枪支是被明确禁止的，而其中一份协议甚至根本不存在。
This is something I even pointed out in the last video.
这一点我在上个视频里甚至还指出来了。
By the Mojang brand guidelines, guidelines that literally do not exist.
根据 Mojang 的品牌指南——一份根本不存在的指南。
Well, it turns out that they do exist as its own hidden internal document under a strict NDA that does contain the prohibitions for guns.
然而，事实证明，这份指南确实存在，是一份严格保密的内部文件，其中确实包含了禁止枪支的规定。
The very same document where Mojang internally recognizes loot boxes as gambling.
也正是在这份文件中，Mojang 内部承认了战利品箱属于赌博行为。
And what pisses me off even more than them trying to apply a contract that was literally impossible to access without whistleblowers was that while they left us on hold for six months because their CEO was on vacation
而比他们试图执行一份若无吹哨人则根本无法获取的合同更让我生气的是，他们以 CEO 在度假为由，让我们干等了六个月。
they officially partnered with Nerf, the gun company
在此期间，他们正式与枪械公司 Nerf 建立了合作关系。
even though these guidelines say that gun-like toys are forbidden.
尽管他们的规定明令禁止枪械类玩具。
Fucking hypocrites.
真他妈的虚伪。
But as you probably guessed it, it only gets worse.
但你可能已经猜到了，事情只会变得更糟。
You see, when buying Minecraft, you create a Mojang account that is then used to play the game.
你看，在购买《我的世界》时，你需要创建一个 Mojang 帐户，然后用这个帐户来玩游戏。
At least, that's how it used to be.
至少，过去是这样的。
Because Mojang was bought by Microsoft in 2014
因为 Mojang 在 2014 年被微软收购了
where just a few years later, Mojang would announce that
几年后，Mojang 宣布
"We've decided that moving forward, all of our games will require a Microsoft account to play.
我们决定，从现在开始，我们所有的游戏都需要一个微软账户才能玩。
And if you didn't want to migrate your account
如果你不想迁移你的账户
you won't be able to log in anymore
你将无法再登录
which means you won't be able to play either.
这意味着你也无法玩了。
" In other words, either migrate your account and give Microsoft all of your data
换句话说，要么迁移你的账户，把所有数据都交给微软，
or they take away what you paid for.
要么他们就收回你花钱买的东西。
And this is what you call a threat.
这就是所谓的威胁。
But not only did they threaten everyone, they also sneakily modified their terms of service to give themselves permission to cancel your account if they simply felt like it.
但他们不仅威胁了所有人，还偷偷修改了服务条款，赋予自己仅凭感觉就可以注销你账户的权利。
And you see, when purchasing a game like Minecraft
你看，当购买像《我的世界》这样的游戏时
that essentially means that you purchased a license to download and play the game where the conditions of that license are within the terms of service.
这本质上意味着你购买的是下载和玩游戏的许可，而该许可的条件包含在服务条款中。
This is important because if a company wanted to change the way a service works
这一点很重要，因为如果一家公司想要改变其服务的运作方式
by, for example, changing their terms of service
例如，通过更改他们的服务条款
that new version would only apply to the new users or the ones that explicitly agreed to the changes.
新版本将只适用于新用户或明确同意变更的用户。
In simple terms, if the contract used to say that you will be able to play the game
简单来说，如果合同过去规定你可以玩这个游戏
if the company doesn't like that anymore, they can't take it away from you because that would be called breach of contract
如果公司不再喜欢这个条款，他们也不能剥夺你的权利，因为这会被称为违约。
which is kind of illegal.
这有点违法。
And what happened here was that Mojang was forcing everyone to migrate
这里发生的事情是，Mojang 强制所有人迁移
saying things like, "You will not be able to access the game.
他们声称：“你将无法进入游戏。
Migration is mandatory.
迁移是强制性的。”
Won't be able to play Minecraft.
将无法游玩《我的世界》。
Must be migrated to a Microsoft.
必须迁移到微软账户。
" Players need to move to a Microsoft account.
“玩家需要迁移到微软账户。”
Mojang accounts to Microsoft accounts.
Mojang 账户迁移至微软账户。
Where funnily enough, they had the balls to say that this was voluntary three times.
有趣的是，他们竟然有胆量三次声称这是自愿的。
So voluntary, in fact, that if you didn't do it
事实上，这种所谓的自愿是，如果你不这么做
they took away what you paid for.
他们拿走了你付费购买的东西。
This was a forced migration, where we obviously didn't have much of a choice.
这是一次强制迁移，我们显然没有太多选择。
The only choice you had was to terminate your account.
你唯一的选择就是注销你的账户。
And not only were they forcing everyone to give-.
而且他们不仅强迫每个人交出——
..
……
their data to a company with a world record of privacy violations
他们的数据给一家在侵犯隐私方面创下世界纪录的公司。
which got recently fined $20 million by the FTC for illegally collecting information on children
该公司最近因非法收集儿童信息而被 FTC 罚款 2000 万美元
most Minecraft players are children.
大多数《我的世界》玩家都是儿童。
But in doing so, they also forced you to agree to Microsoft and Xbox's legal agreements
但在这样做的同时，他们也强迫你同意微软和 Xbox 的法律协议
all under the threat of them taking away what you paid for if you didn't do what they wanted.
如果你不按他们的要求去做，他们就会拿走你已经付了钱的东西，而你一直都处在这种威胁之下。
A contract needs to, uh, be entered into freely
合同的签订必须是……呃……自愿的
and that obviously means that you need to have a
这显然意味着你需要有一个
a choice between agreeing or not agreeing.
在同意与不同意之间做出选择。
Just presenting one choice is not really, uh
只提供一个选项，其实并不能算作……
an agreement.
一种同意。
But even though it was illegal, Mojang still went ahead with it
但即便这是非法的，Mojang 仍然一意孤行
which resulted in millions of people losing access to what they paid for
这导致数百万人无法再访问他们付费购买的内容
some of which were never even notified that it was happening to begin with
其中一些人甚至从未被告知这一切正在发生
only finding out years later that their purchase had been nullified.
几年后才发现他们的购买记录已被作废。
But when actually contacting Mojang to complain, you'd come to find that they wouldn't answer questions
但当他们真正联系 Mojang 投诉时，却发现对方根本不回答问题，
and automatically close most tickets asking for answers.
而且会自动关闭大多数寻求答案的工单。
And when asking Microsoft about it, they would say that.
当我们向微软询问此事时，他们会这样说。
..
"I've discussed your issue with Mojang support and came to the conclusion that the migration is within the Minecraft Terms and Conditions.
“我已与 Mojang 支持团队讨论过您的问题，并得出结论，此次迁移符合《我的世界》条款与条件。”
" In other words, "We've investigated ourselves and found nothing wrong.
换句话说，“我们对自己进行了调查，没有发现任何问题。”
" But unfortunately for them, this user knows his rights.
但不幸的是，这位用户很清楚自己的权利。
And when asking Microsoft to cite his contract for where it says that a Microsoft account is required to play
当他要求微软引用合同条款，说明在哪里规定了玩游戏必须拥有微软账户时
Microsoft said, "End User License Agreements are constantly updated.
微软表示：“最终用户许可协议会不断更新。
Please refer to the current one," where the current one says
请以当前版本为准。”而当前版本写道：
"If you originally signed up through a Mojang account
“如果您最初是通过 Mojang 帐户注册的
you must migrate to a Microsoft account in order to keep using the services.
您必须迁移到微软账户才能继续使用相关服务。
" But this wasn't part of the contract when the user had bought the game
“但用户购买游戏时，合同里并没有这一条。”
to which Microsoft replied, "I understand that this is your interpretation
对此，微软回应道：“我理解这是您的解读。”
but this EULA applies for any user regardless of the date of creation
但本最终用户许可协议适用于任何用户，无论其创建日期如何
" further stating that, "Your contract is the new EULA.
并进一步声明：“您的合同就是新的最终用户许可协议。
The old one doesn't apply anymore.
旧的协议不再适用。”
You agreed to these Terms by using the service.
您一旦使用本服务，即表示您同意了这些条款。
" Where they then immediately closed the ticket
“然后他们立即关闭了工单
refusing to answer any further questions.
并拒绝回答任何进一步的问题。
And this is a perfect example of fucking up in writing
这就是写作中搞砸的完美范例
because it confirms the idea that.
因为它印证了这样一个观点：
..
……
It is up to you to check back to see if these guidelines have changed.
您有责任回来查看这些准则是否已更改。
And that they don't care about agreement, since they claim that you agreed to changes that they didn't even tell you about.
而且他们并不在乎协议，因为他们声称您已经同意了那些他们甚至没有告知您的变更。
So Mojang voided everyone's contract since they say that they don't apply anymore.
所以 Mojang 废除了所有人的合同，因为他们说这些合同不再适用。
And you fucking guessed it, this is breach of contract.
你他妈的猜对了，这就是违约。
And if that wasn't bad enough, when actually looking at the historical changes to the contracts
如果这还不够糟糕的话，当我们实际查看合同的历史变更时，
there used to be a clause that says that you will be able to play the game even if you don't agree to the new changes
会发现曾经有一项条款规定，即使你不同意新的变更，你仍然可以玩这款游戏。
all of which were, of course, sneakily removed during the migration.
当然，所有这些都在迁移过程中被偷偷移除了。
I would say that this, uh, forceful way of
我想说，这种，呃，强行的方式
um, migrating the customers is not a term that is enforceable by Microsoft
嗯，迁移客户并不是一个可以由微软强制执行的条款。
which in this case would mean that they would be forced to reinstate the old accounts.
在这种情况下，这就意味着他们将被迫恢复旧账户。
And all of this is essentially what the class action lawsuit is about.
而所有这些基本上就是这起集体诉讼的全部内容。
Minecraft's success is entirely due to the community making it what it is
《我的世界》的成功完全归功于社区，是社区成就了它。
through, for example, mods and servers, because the base game in itself isn't really that interesting.
例如，通过模组和服务器，因为游戏本体其实并没有那么有趣。
And when the very things that we depend on to actually enjoy the game are being threatened by a company that ignores our rights like this
而当我们赖以享受游戏的这些要素，正受到一家像这样无视我们权利的公司的威胁时，
we as consumers end up being affected because Mojang is restricting the way we're able to play the game.
我们作为消费者最终会受到影响，因为 Mojang 正在限制我们玩游戏的方式。
On top of them literally taking the game away under threat simply because they knew that nobody would be fighting back.
更何况，他们还以威胁的方式强行夺走了这款游戏，就因为他们知道没人会反抗。
But there's a limit to the amount of shit that people are willing to take before taking measures.
但人们的忍耐是有限度的，忍无可忍便会采取行动。
And Mojang?
而 Mojang 呢？
You fucking crossed it, because we're not begging or asking for mercy anymore.
你他妈的越界了，因为我们不再乞求或请求怜悯。
This is a class action lawsuit that you cannot ignore.
这是一场你无法忽视的集体诉讼。
I think this is an important, uh
我认为这是一个重要的，呃
case for this reason that this is becoming a general business practice right now
正因如此，这正成为一种普遍的商业惯例。
and it's not supposed to be like that when you're dealing with consumers
但在与消费者打交道时，情况本不该如此，
especially children.
尤其是面对儿童时。
We are seeing a lot of companies coming out with this claim that you don't get the full terms of service or for their product when you buy it.
我们看到很多公司都声称，你在购买其产品时并未获得完整的服务条款。
The company you're buying from refer you to their
你购买产品的公司会让你去参考他们
uh, contractual terms on the website, which can change at any time
网站上的合同条款，而这些条款随时都可能发生变化。
basically depriving you all your consumer rights.
基本上剥夺了你所有的消费者权益。
And this is not right.
这是不对的。
This is something really needed to, uh
这确实需要……呃
act upon and make sure that we can exer- exercise our consumer rights.
采取行动，确保我们能够行使自己的消费者权利。
And our objectives are quite simple.
我们的目标非常简单。
Revert the account migration, meaning the reinstatement of all unmigrated accounts where Mojang in the EU has to be the owner of all customer data
撤销账户迁移，即恢复所有未迁移的账户，并要求欧盟地区的 Mojang 成为所有客户数据的所有者。
comply with contract and consumer protection laws, so notify about the changes
遵守合同法和消费者保护法，因此请就变更事项进行通知
get agreement for the changes without threatening a consequence for disagreement
在不威胁对方的情况下，就变更事项达成一致
remove unenforceable clauses, including hidden clauses like the one that allows gambling
删除不可执行的条款，包括允许赌博等隐藏条款
clearly indicate when changes happen, and comply with the terms of our old contracts.
明确指出变更发生的时间，并遵守我们旧合同的条款。
I think these goals are re- both reasonable and achievable
我认为这些目标既合理又可以实现
and saying that is coming from looking at what this case is all about
而这么说，是基于对本案全部情况的审视
which is, uh, a big corporation abusing consumer rights and doing so without anybody responding to it would be wrong.
也就是，呃，一家大公司滥用消费者权益，并且在无人对此作出回应的情况下这样做，是错误的。
But as you might have expected, the legal system is kind of complicated
但你可能已经想到了，法律体系是相当复杂的。
because if we take these two examples, even though the core of the issue is the same
因为如果我们拿这两个例子来看，尽管问题的核心是相同的。
our contracts, there's a difference in who was affected by them.
我们的合同，其影响所及的对象是有差异的。
Basically, you need to have the same kind of damage and the same kind of circumstances for everybody that
基本上，你需要确保每个人都遭受相同类型的损害，并处于相同类型的情境中
uh, goes into the class action.
呃，进入了集体诉讼。
So they would each have a different way of approaching it legally
因此，他们各自都会有不同的法律处理方式
some being easier to pursue than others, which is why the account migration is such a great option
其中一些方式比另一些更容易实施，这也是为什么账户迁移会是一个如此绝佳的选择
because you paid for something which they then took from you under threat
因为你花钱购买了某样东西，而他们却在威胁之下将其从你手中夺走
all of which is very easily quantifiable damages
所有这些都是非常容易量化的损失
which basically affected everyone before 2023, including those who did migrate because it was done under threat.
这基本上影响了 2023 年前的每一个人，包括那些已经迁移的玩家，因为他们是在威胁之下迁移的。
And since the account migration is tied to our contracts
而且，由于账户迁移与我们的合同绑定在一起，
just like everything else, we can then use it to resolve most issues with a single process.
就像其他所有事情一样，我们之后就可以用它通过一个流程解决大部分问题。
We need to decide on how we formulate this claim.
我们需要决定如何表述这项主张。
What is the damage that's been done and how are we going to prove that?
造成的损害是什么？我们又该如何证明？
And, uh, actually the evidence is gonna decide for us how we're gonna do this.
而且，实际上，证据将决定我们该如何着手。
And that is the reason for this video
这也就是本期视频的原因
because we are now at the stage where we need you
因为我们现在正处于需要你的阶段
the Minecraft player, to say that you want to participate in the class action lawsuit
需要你，作为一名《我的世界》玩家，表明你愿意参与这次集体诉讼
and to tell us how you were affected so that we can then identify and form the group that will participate.
并告诉我们你受到了怎样的影响，以便我们能够识别并组建参与的团体。
And the more submissions we get, the more likely we are to achieve what we've set out to do and show Mojang that they don't get to do whatever the fuck they want.
我们收到的投稿越多，就越有可能实现我们的既定目标，并向 Mojang 表明，他们不能为所欲为。
Obviously, it's always decided on the evidence and how well we can present that to a court and make them understand what's actually at stake here
显然，这始终取决于证据，以及我们能否将证据清晰地呈现在法庭面前，让他们明白此事的真正利害关系。
which is the consumer's, uh, right to actually resist being abused by a big company.
这是消费者反抗大公司欺压的权利。
Where the first thing I want to say is thank you
首先，我想说声谢谢。
because it's thanks to those donations that we now actually have a chance to fight back in a way that's never really been done before
因为正是有了这些捐助，我们现在才有机会以前所未有的方式进行反击。
and if we win, Mojang will also have to pay back our legal costs
如果我们赢了，Mojang 还必须偿还我们的诉讼费用。
which also unfortunately goes the other way, meaning that I would essentially go bankrupt if we were to lose
不幸的是，反之亦然，这意味着如果我们输了，我基本上就会破产。
which is always a possibility.
而这总是有可能的。
But I don't want to live with the regret of not trying simply because I was too afraid of losing.
但我不想仅仅因为害怕失败，就带着没有尝试过的遗憾活下去。
So bring it on, Mojang.
所以放马过来吧，Mojang。
I'll see you in court.
我们法庭上见。
And even though it feels a little bit wrong to mention it
虽然提及此事感觉有些不妥
we are fighting a billion-dollar corporation that can shit out money faster than privacy violations.
但我们正在对抗的是一个财力雄厚的巨头公司，他们赚钱的速度比侵犯隐私的速度还快。
If you do feel like supporting what we're doing
如果你愿意支持我们正在做的事情
the GoFundMe still exists.
GoFundMe 众筹页面依然存在。